Now that you're a little more familiar with how Window functions work,
والآن وقد تعرفت أكثر على آلية عمل دالة النافذة Window Function،
let's dig into the real power.
فلنتعرف على قوتها الحقيقية.
When using Windows functions,
عند استخدام دوال النافذة،
you can apply the same aggregates that you would under normal circumstances: sum,
يمكنك تطبيق عمليات التجميع ذاتها التي كنت لتطبقها في الحالات العادية: المجموع SUM،
count, average, min and max.
العد COUNT، المتوسط AVERAGE، والقيمة الدنيا MIN، والقيمة القصوى MAX.
The easiest way to understand how these work is to run them all at once.
أسهل طريقة لفهم آلية عملها هو بتنفيذها كلها دفعة واحدة.
We'll just add them to this example from earlier.
سنضيفها فحسب إلى هذا المثال الذي استخدمناه في المرة السابقة.
Let's run through each of these one at a time.
لنستعرض كل منها على حدة.
First, let's look at sum.
أولاً لنستعرض الجمع.
It's creating a running total.
إنه يحسب مجموعاً تراكمياً.
The first row is the same as the standard quantity value 123.
الصف الأول هو قيمة الكمية العادية ذاتها، 123.
The second and third rows have the same value
الصفّان الثاني والثالث لهما نفس القيمة
because they're ordered by the truncated month of occurred at.
لأنهما مرتبان حسب الشهر المُقتطع من العمود occured-at.
Since rows two and three have the same month, they're grouped together.
بما أن الصفّين 2 و3 لهما الشهر نفسه، فقد تم ضمهما.
Similar to the way they're grouped when using rank and dense rank.
على نحو مشابه للضم الذي يتم عند استخدام RANK و DENSE_RANK.
So the value 819 is equal to 123 from
أي أن القيمة 819 تساوي 123
the first row plus 506 and 190 from rows two and three.
من الصف الأول زائد 506 و190 من الصفّين الثاني والثالث.
Rows four and five are also grouped together because they both share the same month.
كما تم ضم الصفّين الرابع والخامس أيضاً لأنهما يتشاركان الشهر نفسه.
Count shows a running count and is grouped in the same way.
أما COUNT فتعرض عداً تراكمياً ويتم ضم الصفوف فيها بالطريقة نفسها.
You can see that rows two and three both show a count of three.
يمكنك أن ترى أن الصفّين الثاني والثالث كلاهما يعرضان العدد 3.
Rows four and five both show a count of five.
فيما يعرض الصفّان الرابع والخامس العدد 5.
Average shows a running average,
أما AVG فتعرض متوسطاً تراكمياً،
which is really just the running sum divided by
والذي هو في الواقع مجموعاً تراكمياً SUM مقسوماً
the running count: 819 divided by three is 273,
على عد تراكمي COUNT: 819 تقسيم 3 تساوي 273،
1430 divided by five is 286.
و1430 تقسيم 5 تساوي 286.
Min shows the lowest value up to that point in the window.
أما MIN فتعرض أقل قيمة تمت مصادفتها حتى تلك النقطة في النافذة.
123 is the lowest value until 85 rolls around.
123 هي أقل قيمة إلى أن نصل إلى القيمة 85.
That's the lowest value in the entire window.
وهي أقل قيمة في النافذة بأكملها.
So it stays at 85 until the next window starts with a count 1,011.
أي أنها تبقى عند 85 حتى تبدأ النافذة التالية بالعدد 1011.
Max works the same way as min,
وتعمل MAX بالطريقة ذاتها التي تعمل بها MIN، 00:01:49,767 --&gt; 00:00:00,000 فهي تعرض دائماً القيمة القصوى حتى الصف المعروض ضمن النافذة الحالية.